### Fiona Cowie | UX/UI Designer

Fc

+447732 601359 | fionajcowie@gmail.com | Edinburgh, Scotland

Design Portfolio: fionacowie.github.io

#### **ABOUT**

Product and UX designer with background in illustration and over 10 years designing customer experiences in retail display. Creative thinker and problem-solver with a strong attention to detail and an analytical approach to usercentred design.

#### **SKILLS**

- UX Design
- UI + High Fidelity Mockups
- Interactive Prototyping
- User Research
- User Persona
- User Journeys + User Flows
- Usability Testing
- Mobile-first Design
- Responsive Design
- Emotional + Visual Design
- Fundamental HTML + CSS
- Code + Accessibility Checks
- Illustration

#### **TOOLS**

- Adobe XD
- Optimal Workshop
- Usability Hub
- Adobe Illustrator
- Keynote

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### User Researcher (Volunteer) | Creative Ethics | Sep 2020 - Present

- Collaborated with a multi-disciplinary team, providing the team with a fast turnaround from research to detailed insight
- Crafted visual presentation tools to help the team understand and meet nuanced user needs
- Conducted stakeholder interviews to define business and user needs, optimise objectives and shape product roadmap

#### Designer/Illustrator | Self Employed | Apr 2017 - present

• Established a personal brand to sell my illustration work

#### Immersive Web Design Project | CareerFoundry | Aug - Sep 2020

- Employed mobile-first design to build a responsive <u>portfolio</u> <u>website</u> from scratch, learning HTML and CSS in the process
- Prepared and ran moderated usability tests on the live site to ensure an accessible site that met project goals and worked for people across different browsers and devices
- Created bespoke illustrations and CSS animations for the site that promoted viewer engagement and curiosity

#### Immersive App Project | CareerFoundry | Jul 2019 - Aug 2020

- Implemented end-to-end user-centred design to create a high fidelity interactive prototype for a responsive web app
- Wrote a UI style guide and <u>design system language</u> that streamlined user needs with visual aesthetics
- Generated research-driven UI patterns and created a mascot that encouraged pro-active user interaction with the app
- Engaged with student community to exchange feedback and expertise, building collaboration while working solo

#### Window Dresser & Merchandiser | Debenhams | 2007 - Mar 2021

 Worked as part of a team to deliver engaging customer journeys that balanced customer needs with business goals

### Fiona Cowie | UX/UI Designer



+447732 601359 | fionajcowie@gmail.com | Edinburgh, Scotland

Design Portfolio: fionacowie.github.io

#### **SHORT COURSES**

- Frontend Development for Designers, CareerFoundry
- Illustrating Children's Books, MATS
- Printed Textiles,
  Abbeymount Studios,
  Edinburgh
- Introduction to Illustration,
  Edinburgh College of Art,
  Edinburgh

#### **EDUCATION**

## **UX Immersion, Design Certificate** | CareerFoundry (Remote Course) | Jul 2019 - Aug 2020

 An immersive, hands-on course covering all aspects of the user-centred design process, from business and user research through to creating a design system and polished UI

# **Bachelor of Design (2:1 Hons)** | Duncan of Jordanstone College of Art and Design, University of Dundee

• Specialised in jewellery design, exploring new materials and the relationship between jewellery and wearer